Guide to the Francis Warrington Dawson Family Papers, 1386-1963 (bulk 1859-1950)
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- 1998 Addition, 1850-1956, (6 boxes)
  - Fragments and drafts of Francis Warrington Dawson II (Box 94)
  - Correspondence, 1866-1929, Oct. 24 (Box 95)
  - Correspondence, 1929, Dec. 4-1950, Sept. 6 (Box 96)
  - Correspondence, 1951-1956, Oct. 30, n.d. (Box 97)
  - Legal papers, 1850, Dec. 18-1948, Mar. 4
  - Financial papers, 1882, May 19-1954, Jan. 5
  - Genealogy
  - Miscellany
  - Writings
  - Clippings, Warrington Dawson (Box 98)
  - Photographs (15 images)
  - Volumes (5)
    Warrington Dawson's handwritten journals, autograph books, drafts, and essays, dating from the 1930s.
  - Volumes (6) (Box 99)
    Warrington Dawson's handwritten journals, drafts, and essays, including History of My Bride, 1929, and University School, Richmond, Va., 1895.
- Oversize and Miscellaneous Materials
  - Maps (Box 100)
    Oversize folder in Box 100 containing encapsulated reproductions of 8 maps from Virginia, New York, and the North American continents, dating from the 1700s through the 1930s, collected by Warrington Dawson from Williamsburg.
  - Photographs (Box 100)
    Oversize folder containing photographs of sculpture, people, and places.
    - Rodin, Augreste (4)
    - F.W. Dawson II (2)
    - Constant, Benjamin J.
    - Chambrun, Charles
    - [Old Ministry of War...]
  - Accession 6/21/88 (Box 100)
    Draft of an undated play, Strange Guests for Dinner, by Francis Warrington Dawson; miscellaneous correspondence.
  - Charleston earthquake photographs, 1886 (Box Image Box 1)
    These images are mounted on cardboard and are approximately 16x20 inches, unless otherwise noted. They are arranged in four oversize boxes, which have been numbered in the catalog as Image Boxes 1-4. Most photographs were taken by C.C. Jones of the U.S. Geological Survey on August 31, 1886. Some photographs have additional captions, added later, written on their cardboard mounts. At least two photographs are personal, and show the Dawson residence following the earthquake.
    - Broken cornice on St. Michael's Church, Southeast corner of Broad and Meeting Streets, Looking Southeast (Box Image Box 1)
    - Brick wall of the city Jail on Magazine Street near Luzon, fissured by earthquake
    - Double exposure of the Granite Works. Dominant image is a yard of granite monuments, some of which have been toppled by the earthquake.
    - Granite Works
    - Craterlet and curdled mud flakes on Ten Mile Hill
    - Sinkhole under a house on Ten Mile Hill
    - Displaced monument, St. John's Lutheran Church, Archdale Street, Looking South
    - Craterlet on Ten Mile Hill
    - Displaced portico of the synogogue on Hazel Street
    - Scotch Presbyterian Church, Cemetary, and Convent
    - Encampment on Capt. Dawson's lawn (6x9 inch photograph) (Box Image Box 2)
    - Capt. Dawson's house (6x9 inch photograph)
    - Gadsden House, Bishop's Residence, Broad Street
    - Wooden house in Lincolnville which was thrown by the earthquake
    - Camp in Courthouse Square, City Park, Broad Street and Meeting Street
    - Gable of a brick house at the corner of Queen and Mazyck Streets.
    - Displaced coping on the portico of the old guardhouse on the southwest corner of Meeting and Broad Streets
    - Hiberian Hall, Meeting Street
    - Displaced monument, St. John's Lutheran Church, Archdale Street, Looking North
    - Large craterlet on Ten Mile Hill (Box Image Box 3)
    - St. John's Lutheran Church, Archdale Street, Looking Southeast
    - Damaged tower and coping of the city hospital on the southwest corner of Luzon and Magazine Streets.
    - Damaged foundations of wooden houses
    - Displaced towers and coping of the city hospital on the southwest corner of Luzon and Magazine Streets
    - Damage to the Old Planter's Hotel, St. Philip's Church, Church Home, and Huguenot Church
    - Damaged chimneys at the southwest corner of Beaufin and Archdale Streets.
    - East Bay Street, with collapsed buildings (Box Image Box 4)
  - Cufflinks (Box Relics Box)
    14 carat gold cuff links which Dr. Bernard Lytton-Bernard of Guadalahara [sic], Mexico, presented to the Dawson Collection on April 6, 1966. He said they were given to Dawson by Theodore Roosevelt and in an impulsive moment Dawson gave them to him.